YEBOAH KWABENA SIMON

Phone · +233 (0) 240090251 / +233 (0) 543031141

Email(s): yeboahsimon918@yahoo.com

GitHub Account Profile: https://github.com/yeboahsimon918

I am a problem solver with skills in resolving problems with minimal supervision. I also like to explore new and upcoming technologies that contributes to my knowledge, experience and career as a software engineer. When it comes to my technology stack, I am experienced in programming languages such as HTML5, Kotlin, CSS3, JavaScript and C++. I am very proficient in typing and multi-tasking,

I also have extensive experience in graphic design which include designing content for a medium-sized firm. Over the last few years, I have regularly worked on graphic-layout, and printing, which has resulted in the development of over 1000+ graphic design projects which includes logos, brochures, advertisements, infographics etc. that increased client transactions by 25%.

I have strong background in project management, customer relations and excellent communication skills, both oral and written.

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2015 – DECEMBER, 2020

DISTRICT TECHNICIAN, KEY TRAINER AND DATA ENTRY CLERK

ELECTORAL COMMISSION OF GHANA – JAMAN NORTH DISTRICT, SAMPA

- Identifying maintenance requirements and assigned repairs to senior technicians
- Setting up and performing technical test on Biometric devices.
- Data Entry into New Biometric Voter Management System
- Verification of recorded information to ensure accuracy and completeness of data.
- Updating relevant electoral files and records.

SEPTEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2019 ICT

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN (NATIONAL SERVICE PESRSONNEL)

NAFANA PRESBY SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL, SAMPA

- Worked directly with departments, teachers and managements to achieve results.
- Part of a team that built and networked a new ICT Lab.
- Built students ability to work collaboratively with others.
- Provided opportunity for students to access and use current technology to solve problems.

MAY 18, 2021 - AUGUST 31, 2021

REGIONAL TRAINER

GHANA STATISTICAL SERVICE – JAMAN NORTH DISTRICT

- Trained enumerators and supervisors on Computer Aided Personal Interviewing (CAPI)
- Updated files, records and setups
- Supervised Enumerators during field work

JUNE 2017 – SEPTEMBER, 2017

SYSTEMS ENGINEER (INTERNSHIP)

BONO REGIONAL HOSPITAL - SUNYANI

- Routine checks and configuration of transmission equipment.
- Repairing of computers, printers, servers and other hospital hardware equipment's
- Troubleshooting
- Providing technical support to employees of the hospital
- Installation of CCTV Cameras

JUNE 2018 – DATE

GRAPHICS DESIGNER & PRINTING PRESS OPERATOR,

YEBOAH GRAPHICS AND PRINTING PRESS OPERATOR – JAMERA - SAMPA

- Hardware and printer repairs,
- Graphics Designs
- All kind of Print Works
- T shirts printing

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2014 - JUNE 2018

BSC. COMPUTER ENGINEERING,

UNIVERSITY OF ENERGY AND NATURAL RESOURCES.

SUNYANI - GHANA

OCTOBER 2010 – MAY 2013

WEST AFRICAN SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL CERTIFICATE,

NAFANA PRESBY SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL.

SAMPA - GHANA

OCTOBER 2010 - MAY 2013

BASIC EDUCATION CERTIFICATE,

JAMERA ROMAN CATHOLIC JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL

SKILLS

- Front End Developer (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript)
- Computer Programming and scripting
 Languages (JavaScript, C++, Kotlin, SQL)
- Web application frameworks and libraries (React, Bootstrap)
- Computer Aided Design and Engineering;
 Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD,
 AutoCAD.

- Version Control and Delivery Technology (GIT)
- Entity Relationship and Use Case Diagram Design
- Project Management Software (Jira)
- Microsoft Office Tools (Word, PowerPoint, Excel)

PROJECTS

1. Frontend of a food ordering web application to be used by various restaurants and food joints using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

2. Frontend of personal portfolios using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS AND PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

1. Participated in a student group responsible for the development of a prototype for a toll collection system which leverages on an RFID and Microprocessor (PIC) technology to be used on the various Road Systems where toll collection causes unnecessary traffic in the country.

2. I captained my school debate team to public discussions about relevant global topics which enhanced my interpersonal communication skills.

REFERENCES

1. Hon. Sieh Kwaku Daniel

District Health Information

Nkoranza North – Busunya

Bono East

Contact: +233 (0) 242 917 363

Email: siehdaniel@gmail.com

2. Mrs. Dina Asamoah

District Electoral Officer (Jaman North)

Contact: +233 (0) 244 014 802

Email: Meyequeen41@gmail.com

3. Rev. Fr. Gyansah Tabiri Simon

Jamera Parish Priest

Sampa Deanary

Contact: +233 (0) 209 417 559

Email: simongyansatabiri@gmail.com